# HITESH BHAYANI

International Tech Park (ITPL), Whitefield, Bangalore

☐ 8550850005 · Miteshbhayani28@gmail.com · in hiteshbhayani

**2+ years** of experience in web and mobile development, Hands on experience in **UI** and **Web Development**. Working on the technology like HTML, CSS, JS, **React**, **Redux** and Node.JS Also worked on 3D, Artificial Intelligence (**AI**) and Machine Learning (**ML**).

# • EXPERIENCE

### NOV 2016 -CURRENT

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, Mu Sigma Business Solutions

- Working on a project for of the **largest retailer** & **fortune 500** client.
- Developed and modified **react components** in a best possible manner.
- Exposed to the best software development methodology.

#### SEP 2016 - NOV 2018

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SLK Software Services

- Developed **Offline** App with open source technologies.
- Exposed to the **HVAC**, configurator and sizing tool.
- **Mentored** fresher in a team and guide them in the project.
- Communicated with customers, understood the requirement and provide the implementation according to it.
- Worked on pre-project activities like **POCs**, **SoW**, etc.
- Worked in R&D lab to find Natural Language Understanding (NLU) solutions for the product.
- Applied Machine Learning (ML) technique in HVAC project.

# SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JS
- Node.JS
- React, Redux
- Saga
- JAVA
- Python

- Dialog flow (NLP)
- Scikit-learn (ML library)
- Web, Mobile & Offline Apps
- Artificial Intelligence
- Machine Learning
- Intelligent Chatbot

# PROJECTS

#### PERSONAL ASSISTANT INTELLIGENT BOT:

- •A **Telegram bot** for the personal assistance like setting alarm, reminders, finding interesting web results, etc.
- •Also integrated with google assistance.
- •Used **Telegram Bot API**, Dialog flow, **IFTTT** and other services.
- •Created dashboard to see the analytics of the monthly activity.

#### **UI FRAMEWORK:**

- No Code framework to automate UI and repeatable actions.
- •Created React like component to make the framework modular and extensible.
- •Used advanced technology like **AI**, **ML** and **NLP** to improve the user experience.

#### 3D WEB VISUALIZER:

- •Handled rendering of different parts of door and windows in the **Three.JS** Screen.
- •Provided **real-time shadow** using **vertex shader** and other Three JS APIs.
- •Used **jQuery UI** to design 2d controls like buttons, drawer and animations.
- •Maintained issue tracker for the team.

## EDUCATION

JUNE 2013 - JUNE 2016

B.E. (COMPUTER ENGINEERING), GUJARAT TECHNOLOGICAL

<u>UNIVERSITY</u>

CGPA: **7.6** / 10.0

JUNE 2010 - JUNE 1013

DIPLOMA (COMPUTER ENGINEERING), GUJARAT

TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY

CGPA: **8.3** / 10.0

#### **MARCH 2010**

CLASS X (SSC), GUJARAT SECONDARY EDUCATION BOARD (GSEB)

GRADE: **DISTICTION**